My wife and I split up. I lost my
pension. I lost my security clearance. I
lost my job. I would do the whole
doggone thing over again.
Really?
Because it was the right thing to do.
And torture is outlawed in this country
now. And I'm proud to have played a role
in that. You come to some issues where
you know that you're right and they're
wrong.
And eventually everybody else is going
to see that. You know, and this is one
of the things when you apply for a
pardon, you have to show proof that you
showed contrition. And I'm not contrite.
Are you sorry for the crime you
committed? No, I'm not. I would do it
again.
Did you ever have regrets? Were you ever
like, "God, why did I do the principal
thing?"
Yeah, when the Justice Department
offered me 45 years in prison and told
me that was the best deal I was going to
get, I intended to commit suicide that
night. And my wife and I were up
watching TV and she said, "Let's go to
bed." And I said, "No, I'm going to stay
up late. I'm going to just watch TV." I
wasn't going to watch TV. I was going to
go down to the garage and just, you
know, put a pipe in my mouth. And she
said, "No, we should go to bed."
And she kind of talked me out of it. So,
yeah, there were times when I I thought,
"Oh my god, what have I done? What have
I done?"
And then, yeah, the more I thought about
it, the more I thought, "No, somebody
had to do it. We're led by a cabal of
criminals.
And somebody had to say something."